http://www.essential-oil-recipes.com/privacy/

Skip to primary navigation Skip to main content Skip to primary sidebar Skip to footerAbout AromatherapyAromatherapy Essential OilsHolistic AromatherapyHistory of AromatherapyEssential Oil ExtractionEssential Oils ChemistryEssential Oil PropertiesSense of SmellAbout the AuthorAromatherapy RecipesAromatherapy Perfume RecipesAromatherapy Body Scrub RecipesNatural Skin CareAromatherapy DiffusersBath and BodyAromatherapy BlendsAromatherapy Home RecipesAromatherapy Holiday RecipesAromatherapy BlogAromatherapy ResourcesAromatherapy BooksAromatherapy SuppliesAromatherapy CoursesAromatherapy Links
Updated May 24, 2018Who we areOur website address is: essential-oil-recipesWhat personal data we collect and why we collect it1. Forms When you submit a message on our Contact form, we collect your name and your email address so that we can correspond with you.2. Google Analytics We use Google Analytics to track visitors on this site. Google Analytics uses cookies to collect this data. In order to be compliant with the new regulation Google included a data processing amendment. The data we collect will be processed anonymously and “Data sharing” is disabled. We don’t use other Google services in combination with Google Analytics cookies.3. Comments When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.CookiesIf you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.Embedded content from other websitesArticles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website. These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.Who we share your data withWhen you purchase a product on https://www.essential-oil-recipes.com, your personal data are shared with well know payment company, PayPal.You can check their privacy policy, PayPal: https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-fullHow long we retain your dataIf you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.What rights you have over your dataIf you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.If you would like us to delete your personal data at any time please submit your email used here: Request deletion of personal data.Where we send your dataVisitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.SecurityTo protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.Changes to this privacy policyWe reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.Contact informationIf you have questions, you can contact us via email at: privacy[at]purpleprodigy[dot]com or mail us as the address below:Purple Prodigy Pty Ltd PO Box 201 Noosa Heads QLD 4567 AustraliaPrimary Sidebar Search Essential Oil RecipesSearch this websiteSponsored Links
Find us on FacebookAromatherapy Essential Oil RecipesFooterPopular RecipesAromatherapy Body Scrub RecipesFacial Clay MaskReed Diffuser Refill RecipeLove Perfume Recipes
